<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>//allee</title>
    <link>https://alleeclark.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on //allee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://alleeclark.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>One SRE’s Struggle and Success to Improve Infrastructure as Code</title>
      <link>https://alleeclark.github.io/post/antipatterns-in-sre/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alleeclark.github.io/post/antipatterns-in-sre/</guid>
      <description>https://thenewstack.io/one-sres-struggle-and-success-to-improve-infrastructure-as-code/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Previous talks</title>
      <link>https://alleeclark.github.io/post/previous-talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alleeclark.github.io/post/previous-talks/</guid>
      <description> adulting.dev Puppetize  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with ttrpc</title>
      <link>https://alleeclark.github.io/post/getting-started-with-ttrpc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alleeclark.github.io/post/getting-started-with-ttrpc/</guid>
      <description>I believe ttrpc stands for teeny tiny rpc. Don&amp;rsquo;t quote me on it. Created for low latency environments based off of the famous gRPC. I was introduced by ttrpc in a talk given by a containerD maintainer. Unexpected for you to know how containerD functions to get started with ttrpc.
This guide is aimed for developers who know gRPC and would like to get started with ttrpc. Knowledge of gRPC isn&amp;rsquo;t required, however knowledge of golang and tcp is needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VSCode Productivity Tips &amp; Tricks</title>
      <link>https://alleeclark.github.io/post/vscode-tips-tricks-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alleeclark.github.io/post/vscode-tips-tricks-1/</guid>
      <description>[Updated 10/3/2019]
More than likely I am a Microsoft developer tool advocate. My first language was c++ using Visual Studio. Haven’t stopped sipping the kool aid since. Even though my primary language is golang today.
Bookmarks Same principle as your web browser. Keep track of places in the code that you know you will need to come back to.
Pros:
 Label bookmarks Side view for all bookmarks per file Search bookmarks  Cons:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Daily Work Routine</title>
      <link>https://alleeclark.github.io/post/daily-sre-routine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alleeclark.github.io/post/daily-sre-routine/</guid>
      <description>The schedule below isn’t the full picture because I normally go on call every few weeks. I spend on call days communicating with other teams and resolving incidents. Bi-weekly attending meetings related to on-boarding, recruiting tech talks, and all hands. I only read work email in the morning unless someone PMs me to review. My company also uses Slack for communication and I limit my time on there as well. This facilitates minimizing distractions and intaking too much information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What decision should I make about an incident?</title>
      <link>https://alleeclark.github.io/post/incident-decisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alleeclark.github.io/post/incident-decisions/</guid>
      <description>This is mainly written from a production engineer’s view. This might be helpful for an engineer who is response for some production service, and just wants a sanity check&amp;hellip; On with the question. Sometimes you have legacy software that most of your company’s critical path relies on. That software hasn&amp;rsquo;t powered off in X amount of scary years. Some combination of documentation, automation of task and source control code is nonexistent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://alleeclark.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alleeclark.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I am Allee. Currently an SRE at Oscar Health working on credentials, service discovery, and observability. Before this I was working on/with data science teams at Dell. Built and supported highly available search clusters for machine learning logs. I&amp;rsquo;ve lived in Texas, DC, and Philly. I love cars. Especially cars with a manual transmission.
I&amp;rsquo;ll Share technical thoughts and post reviews of books and conferences.
A good way to set up a 1x1 is here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://alleeclark.github.io/post/new-stack-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alleeclark.github.io/post/new-stack-post/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archive</title>
      <link>https://alleeclark.github.io/archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alleeclark.github.io/archive/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>